marykay.com 2019-12-29

# Privacy Policy

This Consumer Privacy Policy describes the information that Mary Kay Inc. collects about you. It details how we use that information and the choices you can make about how this information is used. The information covered in this Policy and in the Mary Kay Global Privacy Statement includes information collected about you on Mary Kay websites, and through special programs and services offered by Mary Kay Independent Beauty Consultants or third parties as described herein.

For information about privacy in connection with your visit to the Personal Web Site of a Mary Kay Independent Beauty Consultant, please see the Personal Web Site Privacy Policy tab on this page.

For Independent Beauty Consultants who wish to seek further information about privacy as it relates specifically to you, please see the Independent Beauty Consultant Privacy Policy tab on this page.

Some country laws require country specific information in a privacy statement. Please click here to read that information for those countries.

We are committed to working with you to obtain a fair resolution of any complaint or concern about privacy. We cooperate with country data protection authorities if they believe that a privacy problem has occurred. 

If you have questions or concerns regarding your privacy, please contact us directly.

Mary Kay Global Privacy Team  
16251 Dallas Parkway  
Addison, TX 75001 U.S.A.  
1-800-453-1140

We participate in the U.S. Council of Better Business Bureau’s (BBB) Accredited Business Program. Further information about this program and its dispute resolution process is available at [www.bbb.org](http://www.bbb.org/ "Better Business Bureau website").

Mary Kay is subject to the investigative and enforcement authority of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC).

**Privacy Complaints by European Union Citizens:**

Mary Kay complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries transferred to the United States pursuant to Privacy Shield.  Mary Kay has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles with respect to such data.  If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/). In compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield, Mary Kay commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Mary Kay as listed above.

Mary Kay has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU Privacy Shield, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by Mary Kay, please visit the BBB EU Privacy Shield website at <http://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/> for more information and to file a complaint. 

If your Privacy Shield complaint cannot be resolved through the above channels, under certain conditions, EU individuals may invoke binding arbitration for some residual claims not resolved by other redress mechanisms.  See Privacy Shield Annex 1 at [https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction](http://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction). 

We may collect information about you from a variety of sources. This includes information we collect from you directly; information provided to us by or on behalf of your Independent Beauty Consultant for purposes of providing a better customer experience for you; information we collect about you when you visit our sites or view Mary Kay® online advertisements; and information we collect about you from other sources (where permitted by law).

_**Information we collect directly from you:**  _We collect information directly from you when you choose to participate in our offers and programs or otherwise provide information directly to us. The following are examples of information we may collect directly from you:

  * Name, email address, postal address
  * Username and password
  * Phone number or mobile number
  * Age
  * Date of birth
  * Name of your Independent Beauty Consultant
  * Other information about you and your family such as gender or product use preferences and/or behaviors
  * Demographic information
  * Future communication preferences
  * Contact information for friends you may wish us, or your Independent Beauty Consultant to contact. When you provide us information for these refer-a-friend messages we use the information only to send the message you request.

_**Information we collect when you visit our sites, use our services, or view our online advertisements:  **_We use cookies and other technologies to collect information about you when you visit our sites, use our services, or view online advertisements. The following are examples of information we may collect with these technologies:

  * Your browser type and operating system
  * Web pages you view
  * Links you click
  * IP address
  * Site you visited before coming to our site
  * Mary Kay emails you open and/or forward
  * Mary Kay offers or links you connect to via emails
  * Information about your visits to the Personal Web Site of your Independent Beauty Consultant
  * Your product selections and preferences

## How We Use This Information

We use the information we collect to provide offers, products and services. This information helps us connect you with an Independent Beauty Consultant from whom you can purchase products, tell you about the exciting opportunity to become a Mary Kay Independent Beauty Consultant, and to manage our sites and services, including services for the Independent Beauty Consultants.

The following are specific ways we may use the information we collect about you:

  * Send samples, products and information upon request
  * Develop new and enhanced products and services
  * Enroll you in contests, programs, or offers you request or at the request of your Independent Beauty Consultant
  * In connection with services we offer to your Independent Beauty Consultant
  * Create and manage your account and/or the account of your Independent Beauty Consultant
  * Process payment for purchases or other services for or on behalf of your Independent Beauty Consultant
  * Protect against or identify possible fraudulent transactions
  * Where permitted by law, provide you with customized, unsolicited offers and information about Mary Kay’s products and services through postal mail, including in connection with services provided to your Independent Beauty Consultant
  * Develop and provide advertising tailored to your interests
  * Analyze the use of our products, services, and sites
  * Understand how you arrived at our site and how you use the site so that we can make it better
  * Determine the effectiveness of our advertising
  * Enforce our Terms and Conditions and otherwise manage our business

## Your Choices & Access to Your Information

_**Choices:  **_We give you choices about how we communicate with you.

_**Digital and Electronic Communications:  **_We only send you promotional mobile or email messages if you ask to receive these from us or if your Independent Beauty Consultant asks us to send them to you.

You can stop receiving promotional mobile and email messages from Mary Kay at any time. Follow the opt out or unsubscribe instructions provided in any such message you receive from us or click here to find out additional information about how to let us know which materials you no longer wish to receive.

If you provided information to an Independent Beauty Consultant through her Personal Web Site, you can click here for information on how you may submit a request to your Independent Beauty Consultant regarding your preferences to receive or not receive communications from her through her Personal Web Site.

**PLEASE NOTE:** If you choose to stop receiving promotional messages from us, we will honor your request. However, we will continue to send you service related communications as authorized by law. We may need to keep the information we have collected about you for record keeping, analysis or other reasons, to the extent permitted by law.

_**Access:  **_We acknowledge the right of individuals to access their personal information. We take steps to keep your personal information accurate. You can view, correct or update the personal contact information you provide to Mary Kay. Some Mary Kay programs provide access to view or update personal information online. Check where you registered to learn if you can view or update your information there. If you provided your information to an Independent Beauty Consultant through her Personal Web Site, please contact her directly to update your personal information.

## Cookies, Web Beacons and other Technologies

_**How we use Cookies, Web Beacons and other Technologies:  **_We use these technologies to provide you a richer and more personalized consumer experience. We use internet cookies to collect, and store personal information and other technologies and provide you notice of their use, seeking permission as necessary.  See below for more detail.

_**Cookies:  **_A cookie is a small file placed on your computer by a website that uses the cookie to store information about your use of the website. We use cookies to monitor how our sites are used and to help personalize your online experience. For example, when you register on our sites, we may store a unique code in a cookie on your computer. The next time you come back to the site from that computer, our servers use the cookie to recognize you. We can then use the information you provided when you registered combined with your activities on our sites to provide you a better website experience.

You can accept or decline cookies. Most browsers automatically accept cookies. To learn more about cookies, including how to refuse cookies on your computer, click these links:

  * For Microsoft Internet Explorer: <https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies>
  * <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/cookies/>
  * [http://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en-GB&answer=95647](http://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en-GB&answer=95647)

**_Web Beacons:  _**Web beacons are small bits of code embedded in web pages or in emails. We may use web beacons to deliver or communicate with cookies, to count users who have visited a web page, and to understand usage patterns. We also may include web beacons in e-mails to learn if messages have been opened, acted on, or forwarded.

You can disable the ability of web beacons to capture information in this manner by declining cookies as described above.

**Other Technologies:  **Examples of other technologies we may use to provide better service to you follow:

  * **Web Session Variables** : Information that is passed from one web URL to another as you browse.
  * **Browser plug-ins/add-ons** : Additional web components that may need to be installed to enable certain web features on our sites. You have the option not to install these components.

_**Third-Party Advertising:  **_We may allow third parties, including business partners to display advertising on our sites. Some of these companies may place a cookie on your computer to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. This enables them to understand where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisement and deliver ads that they believe are of interest to you. We do not control these companies’ use of cookies. 

The success of our business depends on your trust, and we do not sell your personal information to marketers outside of Mary Kay unless we have asked for and obtained your consent. We share your personal information only as described below and within Mary Kay.

_Third-party service providers:  _We rely on third-party service providers to perform a variety of services on our behalf and may need to share your personal information with them. Please note that we provide our service providers with only the personal information they need to perform their services and we require that they protect this information and not use it for any other purpose.

For example, we may rely on a service provider to:

  * Fulfill your product and service requests and answer your questions.
  * Host our sites and deliver our email and mobile messages.
  * Mail product samples, contact contest winners, manage payments or take other actions on our behalf.
  * Analyze data, sometimes combined with other sources, to send more targeted communications to you.
  * Conduct research and analyze data to improve our products, services and sites.

We provide these companies with the personal information they need to provide these services on our behalf. We require these companies to protect this personal information and to not use the information for any other purpose.  
**  
_Other situations we may disclose your personal information:_**

  * Where permitted by law, to protect and defend the rights and property of Mary Kay (including enforcing our Terms and Conditions and Agreements).
  * And when required by law, and/or public authorities.

_**Aggregated and non-personal information:  **_We may share aggregated information that does not identify you for general business analysis. For example, we may disclose the number of visitors to Mary Kay sites or services.

Pursuant to the Privacy Shield, Mary Kay remains liable for the transfer of personal data to third parties acting as our agents unless we can prove we were not a party to the events giving rise to the damages. 

We are committed to keeping personal information secure. We have appropriate technical, administrative and physical procedures in place to protect personal information from loss, misuse or alteration.

We limit access to personal information to those who have a business need. We keep personal information only for a reasonably needed amount of time.

When we provide your personal information to our third-party service providers we require those companies to protect the information and to not use the information for any other purpose.

When we collect or transmit sensitive information such as a credit card number, we use industry standard methods to protect that information. 

Please note that we may be required to release an individual’s personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. 

Your personal information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in a country other than the one in which it was provided. This may include the United States. When we do so, we transfer the information in compliance with applicable data protection laws.

We take steps to protect personal information.  Regardless of where this information is stored or transferred, we have the appropriate procedures and controls to help ensure your personal information is protected.

We adhere to country data privacy laws including the EU Data Privacy Directive, as well as the U.S. Department of Commerce EU-U.S. Privacy Shield.

We may transfer personal information to Mary Kay databases in countries other than where it was provided. Our Global Privacy Program requires the same high level of security and protection of personal information in all geographies with procedures and contracts in place to help ensure this is so. Data may be transferred to a vendor or business partner to provide services for Mary Kay, such as targeted email communications, mailing information or samples. These vendors and business partners are required to protect and manage the personal information to the same high standards Mary Kay does, and they cannot use the information for purposes other than to provide the services Mary Kay has requested.  For additional information regarding data transfers click here for country specific information. 

## Children's Online Privacy

We believe it is important to provide added protection for children online. We encourage parents and guardians to spend time online with their children to participate in and monitor their online activity.

We do not intend to collect personal information from children under the age of 14. We ask for an age confirmation in connection with the collection of personal information on our web sites in order to avoid the collection of information from individuals under the age of 14. 

## Changes to This Privacy Policy

We will post changes to this Privacy Policy and update the effective date when this Policy or the Global Privacy Statement is updated. If we make any material changes we will notify you by sending an e-mail to the e-mail address you most recently provided us or by posting notice of the changes on this site.

**Last updated: February 2019**

Online Privacy Statement was initiated in 2004

_2006 Update:  _Provided updated information regarding information security and online privacy.

_2012 Update:  _The 2012 updates were designed to connect privacy compliance efforts in all Mary Kay markets around the world, and to provide consumers, Independent Beauty Consultants, employees and others who may visit our websites with a central location from which they can obtain information about our policies and their rights with regard to personal information. These changes also included updates in compliance with changes to laws in many of the countries in which Mary Kay has operations. 

_2016 Update:_  The 2016 updates are related to the adoption of the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield.

_2019 Update_ : The 2019 updates are related to the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. 

At Mary Kay, we understand the importance of privacy.  Our most important goal is to protect, collect and use personal information provided to us in the spirit of one of our most important founding principles -- the Golden Rule. Your choice with regard to your personal information is important to us and we will use and maintain information only in ways you have allowed. Therefore, we do not trade, sell or lease personal information entrusted to us. This Global Privacy Statement describes how we work to maintain your trust.

We strive to be consistent in how we implement privacy policies across the globe. Our privacy policies are designed to comply with the law in each country where we do business and apply to:

  1. All individuals who provide personal information, such as Independent Beauty Consultants, consumers, customers, research subjects, business partners, shareholders, job applicants, employees, retirees, and others; 
  2. All countries where we operate, even where local regulations do not exist; 
  3. All methods of contact such as the Internet, direct mail, telephone and mobile, and for emerging technologies and methods that might be used. 

Mary Kay manages privacy through our Global Privacy Team, representing all geographic regions where we do business and business processes where personal information is collected—such as from Independent Beauty Consultants, consumer promotions, and employee programs. Mary Kay seeks to promote and utilize industry best practices to ensure privacy concerns are addressed and that personal information is protected.

Our privacy policies are designed to model internationally accepted privacy principles, or fair information practices, such as those established by the European Union (EU) Data Protection Directive and the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce. [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/)

Mary Kay has certified that it adheres to the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access and enforcement. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/).  These principles and how Mary Kay works to apply them are:  

## Why We Collect Information

Mary Kay collects and uses personal information to provide an incredible business opportunity, fabulous products, and services of superior quality for Independent Beauty Consultants and their customers, consumers of our products and services, employees, and others who may come into contact with Mary Kay. We limit the collection of personal information to what we need to know in order to achieve our goal of providing superior quality, value and opportunities. For example, we use e-mail addresses to send Independent Beauty Consultants, consumers, employees and job applicants information they have requested. Independent Beauty Consultant and consumer feedback on products and services is used to improve those products and services. 

We tell individuals what information we collect, how it is used, whether it may be transferred to others to provide the products or services requested, and how to contact the Company or the Mary Kay Privacy Team with inquiries. We provide a link to our Privacy Policies on our websites, and provide additional targeted privacy notices to users who may need additional information about different areas on our websites when appropriate. 

We offer individuals who provide us information choices about receiving further communications from us. Our emails and newsletters are sent only to those who have asked to receive them from us or when requested to be sent to you by an Independent Beauty Consultant. Our communications tell you how to unsubscribe or “opt-out” of receiving future communications. We may ask individuals if they wish to participate in market research, and then contact them if they give us their permission. 

Mary Kay uses technology in order to better serve Independent Beauty Consultants, consumers, employees, and others. We tell individuals when we use technologies that are privacy related. We use internet cookies to collect and store personal information and provide you notice of their use, seeking permission when necessary, depending on the country in which you reside.  

Mary Kay takes steps to make sure that the personal information we use is correct. We provide individuals with reasonable access to the personal information they've provided us so that they can review and correct it, or ask us not to use it.  

Mary Kay protects personal information under company control by industry standard security practices and measures in order to prevent loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure or alteration of the information. We limit access to personal information to those who have a business need for such information. We do not keep personal information any longer than necessary to meet the business purpose for which it was collected unless contractual, legal or regulatory reasons require that personal information not be deleted for certain time periods. 

We may transfer personal information to Mary Kay databases in countries other than where it was provided. Our Global Privacy Program requires the same high level of security and protection of personal information in all countries with procedures and contracts in place to help ensure this is so. Data may be transferred to a vendor or business partner to provide services for Mary Kay and/or Independent Beauty Consultants. These vendors and business partners are required to protect and manage the personal information to the same high standards as Mary Kay. They cannot use the information for purposes other than to provide the services you, Mary Kay or your Independent Beauty Consultant has requested. 

Mary Kay does not intend to collect information from children under the age of 14, or such other age as designated by a country specific law. We ask for age confirmation on our websites before collecting personal information to make sure we do not collect information from children. 

Mary Kay expects our employees and partners to maintain the trust placed in us by those who give us personal information. We provide privacy training to employees and highlight the importance of privacy in our worldwide business conduct program. Those who manage personal information complete privacy self-assessments to make sure that personal information is secure and protected. We periodically audit privacy compliance. 

Mary Kay privacy policies and data protection practices extend by contract to our supplier and partner relationships. We support industry self-regulation as a flexible means for keeping pace with emerging privacy issues. 

For more information or to review a country specific Privacy Policy, click here.

If you have questions or concerns regarding your privacy, please contact us directly.  [Click here](https://www.marykay.com/en-us/pages/countryselector) to select your country and be linked to the correct address or e-mail address to use in your specific location, or use the postal address below. Please feel free to use your native language when sending your questions or comments. 

Otherwise, you can contact us at this address: 

Mary Kay Global Privacy Team  
16251 Dallas Parkway  
Addison, TX 75001 U.S.A.  
1-800-453-1140

We are committed to working with you to obtain a fair resolution of any complaint or concern about privacy. We cooperate with country data protection authorities if they believe that a privacy problem has occurred. 

We participate in the U.S. Council of Better Business Bureau’s (BBB) Accredited Business Program. Further information about this program and its dispute resolution process is available at <http://www.bbb.org/>. 

## Privacy Complaints by European Union Citizens

In compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield principles, Mary Kay commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Mary Kay in your country of residence.

Mary Kay has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU Privacy Shield, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by Mary Kay, please visit the BBB EU Privacy Shield website at <http://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/> for more information and to file a complaint. 

## Notification of Policy Changes

Mary Kay will notify you of major content changes to our Global Privacy Statement by outlining and posting the changes along with the new version on this website. See changes as follows:

**Last updated: September 2016

Online Privacy Statement was initiated in 2004

**

_2006 Update:_ Provided updated information regarding information security and online privacy.

_2012 Update:_ The 2012 updates were designed to connect privacy compliance efforts in all Mary Kay markets around the world, and to provide consumers, Independent Beauty Consultants, employees and others who may visit our websites with a central location from which they can obtain information about our policies and their rights with regard to personal information. These changes also included updates on compliance with changes to laws in many of the countries in which Mary Kay has operations. 

_2016 Update:_ The 2016 updates are related to the adoption of the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield.

Mary Kay is proud to support the efforts of Mary Kay Independent Beauty Consultants through programs such as Personal Web Sites that allow Independent Beauty Consultants an opportunity to reach out to their customers through online tools and convenient round the clock access to information about Mary Kay® products and services offered to you by the Independent Beauty Consultant.

When you provide your information to your Independent Beauty Consultant through her Personal Web Site, your information is placed in a secure location on behalf of your Independent Beauty Consultant. Your information will be shared with Mary Kay but will not be shared with others without your permission. 

## Information Collected on the Personal Web Site

Information that you choose to provide to your Independent Beauty Consultant on her Personal Web Site may include:

  * Name, email address, postal address
  * Username and password
  * Phone number
  * Age
  * Date of birth
  * Name of your Independent Beauty Consultant
  * Skin type, tone and information related to skin care and cosmetic preferences
  * Other information about you such as gender or product use preferences and/or behaviors
  * Demographic information
  * Future communication preferences
  * Contact information for friends or family you may wish for your Independent Beauty Consultant to contact

While on the Independent Beauty Consultant’s Personal Web Site, cookies and other technologies are used to capture information about you and your use of the site. The following are examples of information that may be collected with these technologies:

  * Your browser type and operating system
  * Web pages you view
  * Links you click
  * IP address
  * Site you visited before coming to our site
  * Offers or links you connect to from the site
  * Information about your visits to or from the Personal Web Site
  * “Shopping Cart” information
  * Purchase history

## How This Information is Used

Your Independent Beauty Consultant uses the information you provide on the Personal Web Site to:

  * Provide you with superior quality service
  * Tell you about new products and promotions that may be of interest to you
  * Communicate with you regarding your product orders and preferences
  * Facilitate the sale of products to you
  * Arrange for product orders and delivery
  * Understand your product preferences and send you information or samples
  * Provide you with information about special offers, promotions or contests
  * Schedule appointments or provide information about hosting events
  * Send notifications regarding purchase, payment and shipment information

Mary Kay uses the information you provide on the Personal Web Site to:

  * Facilitate the processing of payment for purchases or other services for or on behalf of your Independent Beauty Consultant
  * Protect against or identify possible fraudulent transactions
  * Assist the Independent Beauty Consultant in identifying your preferences
  * Analyze the use of Mary Kay products, services, and sites
  * Understand how you arrived at the Personal Web Site and how you use the site so that we can make it better for you and your Independent Beauty Consultant
  * Determine the effectiveness of the Personal Web Site
  * Enforce the Personal Web Site and related Terms and Conditions and otherwise manage and secure the site and business
  * Ask you if you wish to participate in market research, and then contact you if you give us permission
  * Facilitate communication or information you have requested from your Independent Beauty Consultant

## Your Choices and How to Access Your Information

When using the Personal Web Site you are providing your information to the Independent Beauty Consultant. Mary Kay has access to your information only for the purpose of providing a service to your Independent Beauty Consultant. However, rest assured that we treat your information provided through the Personal Web Site in accordance with the standards set forth in our Consumer Privacy Policy and our Global Privacy Statement in addition to this Privacy Policy. Please refer to those privacy policies, for further information. Generally, individuals who provide information through the Personal Web Site can contact Mary Kay directly to request to stop future communications directly from Mary Kay in connection with the Personal Web Site. Please contact the Privacy Team for more information or to make a request or click here to submit a request online. You will need to contact your Independent Beauty Consultant directly in order to request that your Independent Beauty Consultant not forward or otherwise send information to you that is not sent directly by Mary Kay through the Personal Web Site program.

You can view, correct or update the personal contact information you provide through the Personal Web Site by contacting your Independent Beauty Consultant. 

## Third Party Service Providers

Your Independent Beauty Consultant may choose to utilize services offered by Mary Kay and third-party service providers to help provide you with efficient high quality service. When utilizing third-party service providers the Independent Beauty Consultant and/or Mary Kay may need to share your personal information with them. Please note that such service providers are given only the personal information they need to perform services requested and they are required to protect your information and not use it for any other purpose.

For example, service providers may be utilized to:

  * Fulfill your product and service requests
  * Host sites and deliver email and mobile messages
  * Mail product samples, contact contest winners, manage payments or take other actions on behalf of your Independent Beauty Consultant
  * Analyze data, sometimes combined with other sources, to send more targeted communications to you
  * Conduct research and analyze data to improve the products, services and sites made available to you
  * Facilitate payment or order processing

We are committed to keeping personal information secure. We have appropriate technical, administrative and physical procedures in place to protect personal information from loss, misuse or alteration.

We limit access to personal information to those who have a business need. We keep personal information only for a reasonably needed amount of time.

When we provide your personal information to third party service providers we require those companies to protect the information and to not use the information for any other purpose.

When we collect or transmit sensitive information such as a credit card number, we strive to use industry standard methods to protect that information.

Your personal information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in a country other than the one in which it was provided. When we do so, we transfer the information in compliance with applicable data protection laws.

We take steps to protect personal information no matter what country it is stored in or transferred to. We have procedures and controls as appropriate to help ensure this.

We adhere to the EU Data Privacy Directive and country data privacy laws, as well as the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce. To learn more about the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield program, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

We may transfer personal information to Mary Kay databases in countries other than where it was provided. Our global privacy program requires the same high level of security and protection of personal information in all geographies with procedures and contracts in place to help ensure this is so.

Data may be transferred to a vendor or business partner to provide services for the Independent Beauty Consultant such as targeted email communications, mailing information or samples. These vendors and business partners are required to protect and manage the personal information to the same high standards Mary Kay does, and they cannot use the information for purposes other than to provide the services Mary Kay or your Independent Beauty Consultant have requested. 

If you have questions or concerns regarding your privacy, please contact us directly.

Mary Kay Global Privacy Team   
16251 Dallas Parkway   
Addison, TX 75001 U.S.A.   
1-800-453-1140

We are committed to working with you to obtain a fair resolution of any complaint or concern about privacy. We cooperate with country data protection authorities if they believe that a privacy problem has occurred.

We participate in the U.S. Council of Better Business Bureau’s (BBB) Accredited Business Program. Further information about this program and its dispute resolution process is available at [www.bbb.org](http://www.bbb.org/). 

For over 50 years Mary Kay has provided limitless opportunities to Independent Beauty Consultants around the world. Trust is one of the cornerstones on which the Company was built. It is in this spirit of trust and our Golden Rule philosophy that we are committed to protecting the personal information we collect about you. 

This Privacy Statement was created specifically with you in mind. It describes the information we collect from Independent Beauty Consultants, how that information is used and protected, and the choices you can make about how we use and share your information. 

We are committed to working with you to obtain a fair resolution of any complaint or concern about privacy.  We cooperate with country data protection authorities if they believe that a privacy problem has occurred. 

In order to provide you up-to-date product and business information for the efficient functioning of your Mary Kay business, Mary Kay collects the following information from or about you:

  * Name 
  * Postal address
  * Email address
  * Username and password
  * Phone number and/or mobile number
  * Date of birth
  * Age
  * Demographic information
  * Family information, including marital status
  * Government identification number
  * Independent Beauty Consultant number
  * Name of your recruiter, Independent Sales Director, Independent National Sales Director
  * Names of individuals recruited by you
  * Product order history
  * Payment information (such as a credit card or financial information in connection with your orders from the company)
  * Commission history
  * Customer Service call information
  * Other information you may choose to share with us in connection to your Mary Kay business or which is shared about you by other Independent Beauty Consultants or consumers

## How We Use This Information

As a Mary Kay Independent Beauty Consultant you are in business for yourself but not by yourself. Generally, we use the information we collect from and about you to provide the products and services you and your customers request and to promote the efficient facilitation of the Mary Kay business opportunity. 

More specifically your information is used to:

  * Send orders, samples, premiums, products and information 
  * Tell you about products, services, promotions and benefits offered by or through Mary Kay 
  * Develop new products and services 
  * Enroll you in contests, programs, promotions or offers you request 
  * Provide you with information about other services that we have arranged through third parties for your convenience 
  * Create and manage your account(s) 
  * Process payment for wholesale purchases or other services 
  * Provide services to help you better serve your customers 
  * Protect against or identify possible fraudulent transactions 
  * Provide information regarding products and promotions from strategic partners and complementary businesses 
  * Develop and provide product information, advertising and business tools tailored to your interests 
  * Analyze the use of our products, services and sites 
  * Understand how you are using our websites 
  * Understand how you are utilizing business tools offered by Mary Kay including personal websites and other e-commerce tools 
  * Determine the effectiveness of our advertising and promotions 
  * Enforce our Terms and Conditions and otherwise manage our relationship with you 
  * Comply with the Independent Beauty Consultant Agreement, Independent Sales Director Agreement and/or Independent National Sales Director Agreement, as applicable 
  * Calculate, process and send commission payments, prizes and awards 
  * Send general correspondence relating to your contracts or relationship with Mary Kay 
  * Comply with our contractual relationship with you and other Independent Beauty Consultants, Independent Sales Directors and Independent National Sales Directors 
  * Manage our sites and services so that we can continue to provide you with limitless opportunities as you engage in your Mary Kay business 
  * Meet any applicable government or regulatory requirements 

## Use of Cookies and Other Technology

We use cookies and other technologies to collect information about you when you visit our sites, use our services or view online advertisements or other information contained on _Mary Kay InTouch _ **®**_ _ or marykay.com. We may also use those techniques to make online browsing more seamless. The following are examples of information we may collect with these technologies:

  * Your browser type and operating system
  * IP address
  * Web pages you view
  * Links you click
  * Mary Kay emails you open and/or forward
  * Mary Kay offers or links you connect to via emails
  * Web Sites which lead you to our site or are visited upon exiting our site
  * Items selected

We use this information to provide you with a more user-friendly experience and to enhance the service and information we provide to you. 

## Your Choices and How to Access this Information

As an Independent Beauty Consultant, it is necessary that we use your information in order to facilitate our contractual relationship with you and others, and to provide you with the most up-to-date information in order for you to be successful in the operation of your independent Mary Kay business. We offer access and choice with regard to your information in compliance with applicable law.  
**  
Choices**

We give you choice regarding how we communicate with you.

**Digital and Electronic Information**

We send you promotional mobile or email messages that you have opted in to receive. Generally you agree to receive these communications when you sign up as an Independent Beauty Consultant or when you join the on-line community available to Independent Beauty Consultants, Independent Sales Directors and Independent National Sales Directors. 

You can stop receiving particular promotional mobile and email messages from Mary Kay and third parties who may send information on our behalf by following the instructions provided in any such message you receive. It may be necessary to continue to send you certain information electronically pursuant to the terms of your Independent Beauty Consultant Agreement and relationship with the Company.

**Postal Mail**

In connection with your status as an Independent Beauty Consultant we may mail you offers, product information and marketing tools that we believe are of interest to you.  While certain materials are necessary to be sent to you by mail in conjunction with your status as an Independent Beauty Consultant, you can stop receiving certain promotional postal mail from Mary Kay. Contact Customer Service to update your preferences. 

**PLEASE NOTE:** If you choose to stop receiving promotional messages from us, we will honor your request to the extent we can do so and still facilitate our agreements with you in relation to your Independent Beauty Consultant status. We will continue to send you service related communications. We may need to maintain the information we have collected about you for record keeping, contractual requirements, analysis or other reasons to the extent required/permitted by law. 

**Access**

We take steps to keep your personal information accurate. You can view, correct or update the personal contact information you provide Mary Kay. Most Mary Kay programs provide access to view or update personal information online including _Mary Kay InTouch_ ® and Personal Web Sites.  If you have any questions, you can contact Customer Service or the Global Privacy Team.

In general, we do not share personal information with marketers outside of Mary Kay. There are circumstances where special offers may be available to Independent Beauty Consultants by third-party companies and in those instances we will only provide your information if we have clearly provided notice and asked for and obtained your consent depending upon your location.  We may share your information with potential customers who have contacted the Company for a referral to an Independent Beauty Consultant, if allowed by law and/or if you give us specific permission to pass on this information to potential customers.  We share information with other Independent Beauty Consultants in order to facilitate contractual obligations pursuant to the Independent Beauty Consultant Agreement, including to your recruiter, Independent Sales Director(s) and Independent National Sales Director(s), for the purpose of honoring our agreements with you and with them.  We only provide personal information needed in order to facilitate support for you and contractual compliance. 

## Third-Party Service Providers

We rely on third-party service providers to perform a variety of services on our behalf. In so doing, we may need to share your personal information with them. Please note that we provide our service providers with only the personal information they need to perform their services and we require that they protect this information and will not use it for any other purpose. We may rely on a service provider to:

  * Fulfill your product and service requests and answer your questions
  * Host our sites and deliver our email and mobile messages
  * Mail product samples, contact contest winners, manage payments or take other actions on our behalf
  * Analyze data, sometimes combined with other sources, to send more targeted communications to you or, at your request, for your customers
  * Conduct research and analyze data to improve our products, services and sites
  * Perform other services that we request

We provide these companies with the personal information they need to provide these services on our behalf. We require these companies to protect this personal information and to not use the information for any other purpose. 

## Sharing of Information within Mary Kay Independent Sales Force

  * For purposes of recognition and awards
  * To facilitate mentorship and connection within the independent sales force community

We may also disclose your personal information:

  * In order to provide first class Golden Rule Service around the globe, we may share personal information with other Mary Kay entities through a protected environment.
  * When required by law, and/or public authorities.

We may share aggregated information that does not identify you for general business analysis. For example, we may disclose the number of visitors to Mary Kay sites or services. 

We may transfer personal information to Mary Kay databases in countries other than where it was provided. Our Global Privacy Program requires the same high level of security and protection of personal information in all geographies with procedures and contracts in place to help ensure this is so. Data may be transferred to a vendor or business partner to provide services for Mary Kay, such as mailing information or samples. These vendors and business partners are required to protect and manage the personal information to the same high standards Mary Kay does, and they cannot use the information for purposes other than to provide the services Mary Kay has requested. 

Mary Kay protects personal information under company control by industry standard security practices and measures, in order to prevent loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure or alteration of the information. We limit access to personal information to those who have a business need for such information. We do not keep personal information any longer than necessary to meet the business purpose for which it was collected, though in some cases, contractual, legal or regulatory reasons require that personal information not be deleted for certain time periods. 

If you have any concerns or questions about the security of your information in connection with Mary Kay or any of our web sites, or if you have any additional questions relating to Privacy at Mary Kay please contact Customer Service in your market or:

Mary Kay Global Privacy Team   
16251 Dallas Parkway   
Addison, TX 75001 U.S.A.   
1-800-453-1140

We participate in the U.S. Council of Better Business Bureau’s (BBB) Accredited Business Program. Further information about this program and its dispute resolution process is available at [www.bbb.org](http://www.bbb.org/ "Better Business Bureau").
